good evening ladies and gentlemen a very
warm welcome to ICICI lumbar General
Insurance company limited's Q4 FY 2024
and fy2 24 earnings conference
call from the Senior Management we have
with us today Mr sanjie mantri MD and
CEO of the company Mr gopal balachandran
CFO Mr alok Agarwal executive
director Mr Girish nyak
Chief technology and health underwriting
and
claims Mr sandip gadia Chief corporate
solutions group and Mr annand singi
Chief retail and government
business please note that any statements
or comments made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance performance as the future
involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being
expressed as a reminder all participant
lines will be in the listen only mode
there will be an opportunity for you to
ask questions after the presentation
concludes should you need assistance
during this conference please signal an
operator by pressing star and then zero
on your Touchstone phone
I now hand the conference over to Mr
sanjie mantri MD and CEO ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Limited thank you and
over to you sir thank
you good evening to each one of you
thank you for joining the earning
conference call of icsl lombar limited
for quarter 4 and financial year
2024 let me give you a brief overview of
the industry Trends and developments
that we have witnessed in the past few
months post this our CFO Mr gopal ban
will share the financial performance of
the company for the quarter and the year
ended March 31st
2024 during the quarter benan economy
continued its robust growth trajectory
with key high frequency indicators
reflecting healthy economic conditions
for the financial year 2024 India's GDP
growth is expected to be
7.6% looking ahead a normal Southwest
Monsoon should support agriculture
activity both toal demand and help
overall
sentiments however any worsening of
geopolitical tension or a global
slowdown may have an adverse
impact now talking about Auto industry
Private Car Sales witness Rob robust
growth for the financial year 2024 aided
by improved supplies and sustained
customer demand as per CM data over 4.2
million Vehicles they sold in the year
the industry also sh saw a shift in the
customer preference from entry-level
cars to SUV thus contribution of SUV in
private car segment has gone up from 37%
to 49% in last two
years as mentioned in the ear last
earning calls uptick in ruler demand saw
two wheer sales grow by
25% in four to touch 4.5 million the
annual two wheer sales also surpassed
the financial year 2020 figure and stood
at 18 million vehicles during the year
around 1.7 million commercial VRE were
sold which was D driven primarily by
good traction and Ina and other core
sectors health insurance continued to be
the largest product segment for the
industry as per data published in the I
annual report for financial year 2023
the growth in number of lives have been
primally given by the group he business
and we expect this trend to continue for
financial year 2024 as well
the commercial line of business witness
growth supported by strong government
capital expenditure related to
infrastructure development consequently
engineering lines of business witness a
robust growth during the
year we remain optimistic that the
industry will continue to grow given the
favorable macros regulatory changes noow
penetration and relatively positive
consumer
sentiments coming to Performance The
General insurance industry Del were a
year on-year gross direct premium income
growth of 12.8% for financial year 2024
excluding crop and M heal the growth
stood at
14.8% overall the combined ratio for the
industry was at 11 12.2% for 9 month
Financial year 2024 as against 11 16.2%
for 9 month Financial year
2023 for motor the combin ratio was at
11 18.2% for 9 month Financial year 2020
4 as against
121.9 for 9 month Financial year
2023 in our last earning call we had
mentioned Improvement in the industry
combin ratio for motor for H1 Financial
year 2024 by fin by 400 basis points to
19.4% from
123.5 for hm Financial year 2023 there
has been a further Improvement of 300
basis points for quarter 3 only in the
combined ratio for motor at 1159 % as
against 11 18.9% during the same period
last year the motor combined ratio for
private players in Q3 financially year
2024 was at
11.7% was at 11.8% for the same period
last year this Improvement indicates a
semblance of discipline coming back to
the
market as you may be aware new motor TP
hike has been announced for financial
year 2025 As We Will Be watchful of how
the industry responds
or to this in coming days now I would
like to touch upon certain regulatory
announcements on March 20th 20124 after
a comprehensive review of regulatory
framework The Authority notified a
number of principal based prescriptions
the new regulations include Den
notification of all tariff notified by
the Earth tariff advisory committee
which contined to be enfor December 2006
with the denotification of the existing
tariff the company is at the Liberty to
design all the general insurance
products in line with its own
underwriting policy this would
facilitate insurers to respond faster to
the Emerging Market requirements and to
design Innovative products to cater to
customers need it may be mentioned that
the pricing of motor TP line of business
continues to be under the Tariff
regime rural social sector and motor
third party obligation prescribes a
minimum insurance business to be
undertaken by the insurers the
compliance and measurement of these
statutary obligations has been revised
in order to enhance the insurance
penetration BMA sugam Insurance
electronic Marketplace resolution allow
for establishment of a digital public
infrastructure Insurance electronic
marketplace with this The Authority has
set out a vision of democratizing
insurance to achieve the goal of
insurance for all by
2047 we believe the regulatory
developments are favorable for the
industry I would like to further
reiterate that the company we will as a
company will continue to leverage the
benefits of being a diversified
multi-product and multi-distribution
organization as we capitalize on the
existing and emerging business
opportunities in the
sector now I will speak about the
business impact for us in quarter 4 and
financial year
2024 the vi by 22% during quarter 4
Financial year 2024
excluding a oneoff transaction in the
motor segment last year growth was 15.8%
which was higher than the industry
growth of
99.5% for
99.5% for financial year 2024 the
company grew by 17.8% as again the
industry growth of
12.8% excluding the oneoff transaction
last year growth for financial year 2024
was
16.4% let me now touch upon our
performance in see business ments during
the quarter and financial year 2024 in
the commercial business segment we
continue to consolidate our Market
position by leveraging our unique
distribution Network enhanced by value
added Services student risk Bas
underwriting and highly rated reinsurer
Capac capacities during quarter 4 2024
we Vi at 11.3% as against an industry
growth of
11% for financial year 2024 we GRE at
14.7% which was higher than the industry
growth of
10% further during the year we acud
market shares across segments such as
fire Marine cargo engineering and
liability as we speak we are at an
industry leading position in Marine
cargo and liability line of business
while being the second largest in Fire
and Engineering line of
business last year we experienced
significant rate hardening in the
reinsurance terms in line with global
Trends however as anticipated the recent
April first renewals have largely been
denyed motor continues to be the largest
contributor to our product mix over the
years we have developed strong
capabilities across distribution
underwriting claims servicing and
actural practices given our presence
across all three Subs segments of
Private Car two wheer and CV we would
continue to balance our portfolio next
depending on the market opportunities as
we saw some discipline return to the
market we scaled up our position in a
cal ated Manner and consequently ended
the year as an industry
leader the growth for us during the
quarter was
27.3% excluding the oneof transaction
last year the growth for quarter 4 2024
was 13.4% as against the industry growth
of
99.6% for financial year 2024 the view
at 12.3% excluding the oneoff
transaction last year the annual growth
was 8.9% against the industry growth of
12.9% the growth in motor segment was
red by strong growth in new Private Car
segment with Vi at 23% for quarter for
2024 and 28% for financial year 2024
which was higher than CM volume growth
of 12% and 8.4% respectively a new two
wheer growth was 11% for quarter 4 and
13% for financial year 2024 while the CM
volume growth was 24.9% and 12.3%
respectively as real demand picks up we
expect to see the trend continue for two
wheelers in the new CV segment we degre
by 2.1% in quarter 4 2024 and 1.9% in
financial year 20124 while the CM volume
growth was .1% and 14.4%
respectively for financial year 2024 are
mixed of Private Car two wheer and
Commercial Vehicle stand that 31.4 %
26.8% and 21.9%
respectively we also continue to build
efficiency in motor claims in quarter 4
2024 we were able to service 70% of our
agency and direct claims through
preferred partner Network up from 54% in
quarter for
2023 for the next year we expect MX
single digit growth in Private Car Sales
while the two wheer segment is expected
to deliver 8 to 10% growth CV sales are
expected to grow in double digits in
line with the previous year on account
of demand from infas sector the health
the health segment continued to be the
fastest growing segment for the industry
we grew faster than the industry both in
quarter 4 and financial year 2024
registering a growth of 29% for the
quarter and full
year the group health employer employee
segment we 31.7% in quarter 4 2024 and
30.3% in financial year 202 four the
change in the underlying industry
pricing sentiments resulted in customer
moving towards insurance with Superior
servicing
capabilities our retail sales business
grew by 21.8% in quarter 4 2024 against
the industry growth of
19.9% for financial year 2024 our retail
growth view retail business view at 20%
as against and the industry growth at
19.1% we would continue to invest in
this segment in terms of human
technology human uh human capital
technology and knowledge Capital to
further improve our market share our
current
details agency manager count stands at,
1600 we will continue to strengthen our
growth L work as we expect to achieve
far more than far more in this
segment our bank insurance and key
relationship grew at 15.7% for the
quarter and 20.2% for the financial year
2024 within this icsi group distribution
view by
39.4% for quarter 4 Financial year 2024
and 22.5% for financial year 2024 we
will continue to deep mine our existing
Relationships by creating new value
streams and at the same time focus on
acquiring new relationship during the
year we added over 80 Banker
Partnerships in our last call we spoke
about a vision of one is one team under
this one of our initiative that we have
outlined in our one eye is our one is
one digital strategy through this we aim
to consolidate our customer facing
digital assets of I take care websit and
alliances along with our distribution
facing front end this will allow us to
exploit the synergies across all our
platforms which will result in benefits
to the
company our onetop solution for all
insurance and wellness need the I take
care app has surpassed 9.3 million user
downloads till dat we continue our
growth momentum with 8 million user
downloads for the quarter in the same
period we sour premium over 1.13 billion
and a premium of 3.68 billion for
financial year 2024 registering a 3X
increase on a Yi
basis our overall customer facing
digital business grew at 29.5% in
quarter 4 and 39% in financial year 2024
and constitute 6.8% and 6% respectively
of of our overall business last week we
announced a strategic tie up with policy
Bazar our tie up is aimed at Levering
leveraging the strength of the two
institutions to create a superior
customer value
proposition after transitioning to Cloud
we have continued to make significant
Investments on modernization of our
technology
platform along with this our Core
Business and Technology transformation
project project Oran is also under Way
project tan would entail three pivotal
pillars of reimagining processes with a
digital first approach modernizing
technology by shifting away from Legacy
systems and enhancing stakeholder
experience to Superior en engagement
models we are excited to share that we
have kickstarted the transformation
Journey with some of our preferred line
of businesses and are witnessing the
initiatives shaping up nicely we firmly
believe project toan will be a key
enabler on a vision of one Isle one team
as the EMP on the new Financial Year we
will focus on leveraging our
multiproduct multi-distribution strategy
through effective use of data digital
advancements and launching new products
will maintain focus on scaling up our
profit P while continuing to grow as one
Al one team now I would request gopal to
take you through the financial numbers
for the year for the Recently concluded
quarter and the year thanks s and uh
good evening to each one of you
I will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the
recently concluded quarter and financial
years we have uploaded the results
presentation on our website you can
access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers during the quarter
IC Bank acquired additional Equity
shares of the company consequently the
shareholding of the bank in the company
has increased to more than 50% and the
company has become a subsidiary of the
bank Ross direct premium income of the
company was at rupes 27.76 billion in
f24 as against R 210.25 billion in fi23
a growth of
17.8% which was higher than the industry
growth of
12.8% excluding crop and mass heal the
gdpi growth of the company was at
17.1% which was higher than the industry
growth of 14.8% in fi 24 GDP of the
company was Ates 60.73 billion in
quarter for fi 24 as against 49.77
billion in quarter 4 fi23 a growth of
22% this growth grow was higher than the
industry growth of
99.5% excluding crop and mass Sal gdpi
growth was at 22% which was again higher
than the industry growth of 13.8% in
quarter 4
fi4 our gdpi growth during f24 was
primarily driven by growth in the
preferred segment the overall gdpi
growth of our Property and Casualty
segment grew by 14.7% at rupes 68.5
billion in f24 as against R 59.73
billion in f23 on the retail side of the
business GDP of the motor segment was at
rupes
96.34% the advanced premium was at
rupees 33.3 billion at March 31 2024 as
against R 33.4 billion as at December 31
2023 GDP of the health segment was at
61.71 billion in f24 as against R is
47.825445
29.1% our agents which included the
point of sale distribution count was at
128 411 as on March 31 2024 up from
12588 as on December 31 2023 during the
year we witnessed catastrophic events
namely Cyclone Vier jooy North Indian
floods and Cyclone Mong resultantly
combined ratio was 13.3% for the full
year fi 24 as against 10 14.5% for
fi23 including the impact of these cat
losses of rupes 1.37 billion for the
full year the combin ratio would have
been at 1 10
12.5% for the quarter combin ratio was
10 12.2% in quarter for f24 as againsted
10 14.2% in quarter 4 of fi23 our
investment assets Rose to rupes 48907
billion as at March 31 2024 up from
rupes 4686 7 billion as at December 31
2023 our investment leverage net of
borrowing was 4.09 times as at March 31
2024 as against 4.11 times as at
December 31 2023 investment income was
Ates
35.262781
this year as against 8.17 billion in Q4
of last year our capital gains net of
impairment investment assets
stood at R 5.51 billion in f24 as
compared to R 4.53 billion in
fi23 capital gains net of empowerment
investment assets stood at R 1.56
billion in quarter 4 fi 24 as compared
to rupe 1.59 billion in quarter 4 fi23
our profit before tax grew by 21% at
2.55 billion in fi 24 as against R 21.13
billion in fi23 whereas profit before
tax grew by 21 .9% at 6.98 billion in Q4
f24 as against 5.73 billion in Q4
fi23 consequently profit after tax grew
by 11% at rupees 19.19 billion in f24 as
against rupes
17.29% in f24 profit after tax grew by
18.9% at R 5.2 billion in Q4 fi2 24 from
R 4.37 billion in Q4
fi23 the board of directors has proposed
a final dividend of R 6 per share for fi
24 this payment is however subject to
approval of shareholders in the uing
annual general meeting of the company
the overall dividend for fi 24 including
the proposed final dividend is rupees 11
per share last year the overall dividend
was R 10 per share return on average
Equity was 17.2% in f24 as against 17.7
% in fi23 return on average equity for
the quarter 4 fi 24 was 17.8% as against
17.2% in quarter 4
fi23 solvency ratio was at 2.62 times at
March 31 2024 as against 2.57 times as
at December 31 2023 continued to be
higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement of 1.5 times as I conclude I
would like to reiterate that we continue
to stay focused on driving profitable
growth sustainable value creation and
safeguarding interest of policy holders
at all times we would uh we would like
to thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we'll be happy to take
any questions uh at this point Thank
you thank you very much we will now
begin the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on their Touchstone
telephone if you wish to withdraw
yourself from the question queue you may
press star and
two participants are requested to please
use handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will now wait
for a moment while the question Q
assembles the first question comes from
the line of Shrea Shivani from clsa
please go
ahead thank you and um congratulations
on a good set of numbers I have three
questions uh so first is on the overall
growth Outlook so a health book for us
as done quite well since past two years
since F22 the growth has been north of
25 30 40% right uh so
so um expecting some moderation and
growth going ahead what will be the key
drivers for growth in F
2526 uh which segments would be driving
majority of the growth and how much
higher than industry growth can we
deliver in the years to come given that
motor segment is still the the combin
ratio is still though there has been an
improvement and discipline has come in
but it's still quite a high combined
ratio for us to for one to expect us to
grow very fast in the motor segment so
that's my first question on he growth
drivers and how much faster than
industry can we grow in fi 2526 uh
second is on the motor TP segment uh
looking at the reserve triangles
reserving triangles for the motor
segment CP segment specifically so there
has been a much higher Reserve release
in accident year 18 1920 I mean the
trend looks much better than the
previous prior year Trend so how should
we read this data does this also
significantly add to your fi 24 loss
ratio Improvement on YY basis uh apart
from more new cars being sold um so
that's that's my second question and Sir
on the third question is on the combined
ratio we've done quite well on the
combined ratio side um already at 100
for the fourth quarter that has G gone
by much better uh numbers over there so
um going ahead what is our guidance on
combined ratio and one question that I
also asked at the an meet about uh
considering uh natural calamities as
business as usual going ahead does that
change our combined raal guidance in any
these are my three questions thank
you
so take the other one I'll tell you what
is our yeah so I think uh if you look at
uh on the first one sh I think uh if you
look at it from an overall Market
perspective uh I think as we have always
been saying we have been we have always
been looking at this business in the
context of being multiproduct multi-
distribution setup and therefore to that
extent different segment of businesses
uh presents opportunities for growth
maybe at different points of time and
hence to that extent is where I think we
have been able to kind of put in place a
model in place by which we are able to
leverage the growth potential uh so and
it is in that context when you look at
the overall year gone by I think we have
been able to have an outperformance
relative to the market growth and if you
look at in terms of how we are heading
into the next next year I think there's
a lot of positive momentum that we see
from from an overall Market perspective
as well one of course this flew of uh
regulatory reforms that we spoke as a
part of the introductory uh remarks I
think that augur well both from a market
standpoint and even from the opportunity
that it gives for Isis Lombard I think
is very very positive second I think if
you look at the thrust that the
government is putting on in terms of in
general looking at significant Trust of
infrastructure development that
obviously presents a lot more
opportunities on multiple segments of
businesses whether you look at it in the
commercial line space uh maybe for
example uh thrust on engineering
projects to begin with obviously to that
extent it kind of AIDS in logistics uh
transportation to again look at uh
growth profitably and more importantly
it is also expected to lead to let say
higher number of uh jobs and therefore
to that extent it like as I said kind of
augur very well
in terms of the opportunity that one
sees specific to your point on health I
think as we have always said even in the
past I think uh the kind of opportunity
that one sees in the market if you look
at few years back the market was
significantly stressed in terms of the
loss experience or and more importantly
whether you look at it from a combined
isue standpoint given that some of the
players are already kind of looking at
uh reversing some element of pricing
within group wealth and particularly on
the employer employee side it obviously
kind of aers well and that's the reason
why you see us uh continuing to grow
disproportionately relative to the
market and even as we head into
fi25 We Believe health for or the
industry as will continue to be by far
the one of the fastest growing segments
and within that even for IU Lombards we
see an opportunity on health both in the
groups Health as well as from the retail
Health segments uh so that's whe whether
the growth will be continuing to be at
25 will it slightly get moderated I
think we will obviously wait for things
to evolve but honestly as they have said
even in the past I don't think uh from a
market perspective we will continue to
see prolonged periods of 25 to 30%
growth from an industry stand point so I
think that's something that we will
obviously watch for the second question
on yours in terms of the motor third
party reserving triangle I think uh it's
good that the market is starting to look
at the triangle disclosures from an
overall Market perspective I think that
again aers well because then every
company is being kind of proed to
appropriate uh level of scrutiny from a
market perspective and to that extent it
again uh aers well from overall Market
discipline uh in terms of uh uh the some
of the let's say the releases that you
spoke about I think if you ask us the
way I would kind of respond to it is
whether have we is there any change in
the approach of our reserving philosophy
the approach is not changed and in line
with what we have been speaking even in
the earlier quarters I think the way to
look at on the third party book as you
rightly mentioned is more more on an
annual basis and in fact if you
recollect uh even last time in the
quarters earnings call we did speak
about a range within which we see the
loss experience play out for motor as a
category and just to kind of refresh
that we had said motor own damage loss
experience is something that we see in
the range of 60 to 65% and motor third
party is a segment we had said we would
be kind of operating at a range between
65 to 70%
and both of that Blended is where we had
said motor as a category would run in
that range of 64 65% and if you look at
the full year numb both on motor own
damage as well as on motor third party I
think broadly the outcome of the book
that we have been able to underwrite has
been within that range that I just kind
of uh refreshed having said that one of
the key deliverables that we would
obviously watch for which also put which
we put as a part of the uh introductory
remarks is on motor third party pricing
now as we speak statement of fact is we
have not seen a price change so we will
watch for development in that space and
therefore to that extent the risk
elction will continue to be driven by
some of the factors that we see as speak
in terms of no price increase thus far
so we will be guided more by that in
terms of how we see the opportunity the
range of loss experiences is a function
of what I kind of mentioned your last
point on combined
ratio I think uh sh clearly I mean the
quone numbers from command ratio which
read
102.2 and they about where does it play
overall commentary in terms of what we
spoken tail events available sectoral
reform which are being initiated by the
regulator uh we see a play and we do see
that we can have a you know over 50
basis Improvement further to what we
have said we will achieve as a team by
quarter four of next year uh but uh
again we will keep revisiting and
absolutely will keep communicating we do
see green shoots and that kind of an
improvement can come in overall for us
as an
entity so so what you're saying
basically by fi25 we were targeting 102
that can be uh 50 BS uh lower at 101.5
unless there is some other and what
about the catastrophe events are we are
we still watching it or have we come to
a conclusion on how we should be dealing
with yes so clearly I think gopal also
in the past has been mentioning that the
frequency of catastrophic event on an
annual basis uh has got increased and do
we factor that when we speak about it
yes there is a level of factoring but
like a last year was an exceptional one
which was more than the factoring that's
why we keep sting in terms of what would
have happened if those Cat event would
not have been in terms of quantum to
that extent uh see in the business of
writing risk at a fundamental level do
we was do we Factor all of that is part
of the process but the EXT the extent to
the event is something which we all
await uh we will keep you updated on
that part but there's some element which
obviously is Big de when we see that uh
we are overall expecting an improvement
of 50 basis points okay thank thank you
this is useful thank you thank
you ladies and gentlemen we request you
to please restrict your questions to two
questions per
participant we have the next question
from the line of sanket Goda from when
is spark please go ahead uh yeah thank
you thank you for the opportunity I I
have two key question uh one one
question is with the with respect to the
regulation um just just my my
understanding of that new obligation
Norms on motor TP seems to be more
stringent than it was in the previous
regime so so just wanted to understand
whether whether we would be confident to
fulfill the obligation of motor TP in
the new Norms uh is is the point we
wanted to I mean just wanted to
understand and and how you will achieve
that's that's one question and and
second strategic question which I want
to understand is that you have
highlighted about one L um but but if
you want to quantify the number uh due
to one L what are the synergies you are
expecting to see either in the form of
gwp growth because because you now
aligning agents across the business
segment or distribution across the
segments so so so you expect the
synergies and and it mean quantify the
number in terms of gwp additional gwp or
or maybe an additional Improvement in
the expense ratio because of these
Synergy and and lastly on data keeping
uh uh if you can share retail and Group
Health loss ratio and and goal to last
Point sorry that that if the no TP price
high do Inc come are you still confident
that 65 to 70 motor off isue is
achievable or
not okay so I will take the first two
and then the other
one the data that you seing in the last
question goal will will come in and give
it to you uh in terms of the new TP
regulations that have come in see I mean
the insurance The Authority has clearly
said that they're looking for insurance
for all by 2047 and for that some
initiation has to be done uh the conus
of how this will uh emerge for all of us
has still to emerge uh it's kind of work
in progress but that being said see we
are multi-and multiproduct well
distributed franchise is so much of
retail I mean the am
with do as an entity zong us so we are
present we would definitely back
ourselves to
achieve uh the objectives that are set
by the regulator but we would be
speculating beyond the point as to where
we where we will be placed that we have
complete Clarity in terms of what's
expected from us so that's Point number
one under one one uh one team that we
have been talking about and really
emphasizing uh quantification
fundamentally comes with the qu results
that you will see us announcing and we
would uh refrain from attaching uh you
know finite value because the overall
performance is subject to scrutiny which
we keep announcing to all of you and uh
uh are we excited in terms of uh seeing
both Top Line and cost getting you know
controlled in a relatively better manner
the answer is yes definitely and we do
believe coming quarters will ACR uh but
we not be you know calling it out and
calling that this is happened because of
this overall the efficiency of the
company will be you know will be
reflected in how we perform as an entity
and there are multiple other aspects
that come you know we may have some
genuine savings we may choose to
reinvest also that so we would not like
to you know Dell on this on those
aspects but you give a 50 basis point
better guidance than than what it was
last year so so is it because of this
one what you are trying
to again what what I would again you
know you know rush into I get from where
your excitement is coming from this
would be one of the controls we always
maintained that the industry sentiments
also has to move in the positive
direction we always maintained the fact
that we would be an output of where the
overall industry growth is and how our
own placement is so is this an element
that comes in and binds us together as
an organization 110% answer is yes uh
but to quantify this this from this
output this much has come because of
will not
be will not be fair is all I'm saying so
there are multiple things that go in
that for the other two questions that
you I goal to rever to you yeah so so
sank on the health loss numbers uh again
I'll give you Q4 numbers first and then
I'll will give you the full year number
Q4 on the uh ghi which is employer
employee segment this is for quarter
four of last year which is f by 23 that
number is at
93.2% that number for quarter four of
this year is at
88.1% uh and on a full year basis for
the same segment I think the range that
we have spoken about is to operate in
the range of 94 95% if you look at fi23
the overall loss ratio on the ghi side
was
95.2% and this here we are at about
93.7% on retail Health again just to
kind of refresh uh what we have talked
about even in the past several quarters
is we comfortable operating in the loss
show range which is between 65 to 70% in
that context when you look at the
quarter 4 fi23 numbers retail which is
on the indemnity side that loss ratio
was about
61% that number for quarter four of this
year is at
64.6% and on the full year basis last
year number was
64.1 and the current year number is at
about 65.4
uh so that's in in response to your
second point on the health loss numbers
the last question of yours in in terms
of uh whether the range that I spoke
about of 65 to 70% in the context of
motor third party uh so again I think
that's the range that we have kind of
largely operated at I think the only
factor that I would say is uh in line
with again what we've been speaking even
in the past few quarters as in to say
that what we are seeing on ground is
also maybe an in increased preference
of the course to start giving
compensation in favor of uh the victims
of the insured and therefore so that's a
trend that we will obviously observe uh
the other factor which would again uh
which we have which we have again spoken
of which should be directionally
positive is also this whole six months
law of limitation in terms of how that
gets laid out uh last year of course we
did see some developments and finally as
we have been saying the matter is
presently at the Supreme Court once the
verdict come out I think we will again
have to see in terms of how that place
gets paid out on ground so hence there
are again balancing forces in terms of
ones that could possibly see or reflect
an increase in the loss experience
that's really then it's up to us in
terms of what kind of risk selection do
we do and the second is more a positive
benefit at least for I Lombard from an
over overall Ro standpoint and end to
that ex that that should kind of Aid Us
in terms of maintaining the loss isio
range of 65 to 70% so there are lot of
moving parts now at this point of time I
think we would want to kind of stick
with uh the 65 to 70% range and of
course we will see some of these factors
in terms of how that get paid out
through the
year perfect thanks thanks for your
responses thank you than thank you thank
you thank
you the next question is from the line
of nides from investtech please go
ahead uh thanks for the opportunity uh
first question is on IFRS so any uh any
updates what are the timelines for
expected implementation of IFRS and what
impact on our and balance sheet
of so NES I think again in line with
what I had mentioned even in the last
earnings call I think we had said that
uh we are pretty much uh progressing
well in terms of doing the impact
assessment making sure that we get
ourselves ready for the implementation
which is effective from fi 2526
Financial year uh and even last quarter
we did say that we will come back in
maybe a couple of quarters time frame so
honestly internally while we are doing
all of those and also watching for uh
the developments in terms of all the
necessary guidelines and standards
getting issued in the context of the
IFRS transition so therefore at this
point of time too early to call out but
as I always maintained I think we have
clearly spoken about three or four key
uh areas or aspects which is where we
would likely to see the impact of
transition playout in the country
context of IFRS so that doesn't change
um whether it is in terms of acquisition
cost whether it is in terms of
discounting of reserves whether it is in
terms of Mark to Market on the
investment book and maybe for few set of
companies which have kind of issued uh
let's say stock units or stock options
so there will be an element of cost
through the earnings so those are three
or four key areas where one would see an
impact of the transition playout
specifically to call out I think we will
come back and obviously keep all of you
updated in terms of uh where we are on
the
for sure sure and secondly in terms of
solvency ratio we are operating at
significantly higher number threshold uh
and our Roes have also now improved to
17 to 18% uh so do you think of vation
of capital going
forward no of course that's obviously
something that we kind of uh uh is
something that we always look for uh I
think one of the factors that you see
which also led to let's say Improvement
in Sol VY and of course Improvement in
earnings over the last few years has
been our approach to as what sanj has
also been talking about is to sustain
profitable growth as a theme and hence
in let's say relative to the market I
think we have been slightly slowing
going slow on some of the segments and
therefore to that extent we have not
been able to completely utilize the
solvency Capital what we are seeing is
what we kind of put out as a part of the
introductory remark which is to say that
on ground we are seeing semblance coming
back in uh some of the segments where we
have we have been a bit cautious and
therefore to that extent as we see let's
say incremental growth play out in line
in line with our approach to continue to
grow as well as kind of remain
profitable obviously there will be
consumption of capital that one would
see uh in terms of uh the way forward uh
and secondly I think the approach of the
philosophy that isos has always worked
with is to be slightly more prudent in
terms of the level of solvency that we
want to maintain given the fact that the
Indian market still continues to operate
on a solvency one regime while again uh
thanks to the regulator they have been
significantly working on getting the
market again transition to a risk-based
capital regime obviously we will get to
know more in terms of the firm date of
implementation in terms of the
transition uh so hence that that that's
something again that we will see in
terms of how does that result into in so
far as the consumption of capital is
concerned so while we do see growth
opport ities and to that extent we
believe we will continue to use the
capital
judiciously so and just lastly on the
provision for diation in value of
investment around 68 crores what is the
reason for that and when we disclose the
capital gain number excluding this
rejoin the que for followup
questions okay sir thank
you the next question is from the line
of PR Jen from moil La oswal please go
ahead uh uh yeah hi good evening uh so
firstly just a clarification when you
say 101.5 as a guidance that is for the
exit rate of 24 of next year or it's for
the uh full year uh secondly if I you
know like just uh just going back to one
of the uh previous questions on the
motor TP business on your you know the
obligation if the share of CV goes up do
you still uh believe that that you know
65 to 70% guidance can be maintained um
and with that you know gopal time and
again you know we've seen Q4 loss ratios
improve sequentially increase
sequentially for motor TP is it just
because of the adverse judgments that
come in Q4 or what is it that really
gives that kind of a loss ratio uptrend
in every fourth quarter uh yeah I think
those would be my good questions yeah
yeah maybe I'll take the
the uh uh TP loss isue part first uh I
think Whenever there is let's say
possible uh reduction in the TP loss
rati the questions gets asked the other
way around and therefore to that extent
uh I think as I think I have always kind
of maintained that this is a book which
is much more longtail in terms of loss
development and therefore to that extent
given the nature of the business you
will always see cyclicality SL
fluctuations in the law experience of
the book in terms of its outcome so
therefore which is why I keep harping on
looking at the numbers ideally over
longer term but definitely not between
quarters look at it more on an annual
basis um and as I keep saying again
there are various factors that
influences uh let's say the Lost
experience of the book I think uh so
hence to that extent you will get to see
fluctuations in the CP loss ratios
across Quarters on a full year basis is
what I spoke about in terms of trying to
maintain us operating at a segment uh I
mean segment loss ratio in that range of
65 to 70% uh now coming back to your
first second part of the question in
terms of link to motor third party is
the obligation now obviously the the
obligation is something that is
applicable to Industry at large and
therefore as as a company I mean uh we
have to make sure that we kind of meet
those uh obligations and I'm sure we
will have in place a plan by virtue of
which we are able to meet uh the
regulatory expectations I think the the
thought in terms of where the regulator
is coming out with the need to bring
about this change is again very very
positive because the whole thought
process is to try and make sure that the
industry kind of comes under the Ambit
of insurance and to that extent that's
very very positive and if you're able to
do as as an industry if you're able to
work collectively and maybe bring the
larger set of let's say uninsured
vehicles within the Ambit of insurance
that to my mind is a great positive and
hence to that extent uh I think we would
obviously work and make sure that we
able to meet those uh o applications of
the third party side uh the first part
on the combined ratio uh uh part I think
obviously yes I think directionally the
lens that we have talked about mes is is
that we have we have been saying that
directionally the uh trajectory for us
is to bring down the combined over a
period of time and obviously this has to
be looked at in the context of how we
see the market environment operate act
uh which is why I think even as a part
of of the introductory remark we just
point out to say that the Market is
clearly showing signs of at least from
the reported numbers on a 9 Monon basis
There is almost a 400 basis point
Improvement in Combined from an overall
Market perspective and within that one
of the key segment which has been a
larger contributor of significant
competitive intensity has been motor
that's again a segment which has again
not just on a half yearly basis even if
you look at the quarter quarter three
numbers for the market that's again
shown an improvement of almost about 300
basis point so which is why I think we
kind of put out to say that there seems
to be some kind of a semblance coming
back and that's also getting reflected
in terms of the growth numbers that many
of these players were exhibiting in
terms of competitive aggression clearly
you can see a lot many players are
starting to find a pullback so that
gives us possibly some kind of a
confidence uh in terms of how do we look
at achieving that uh combined objective
that we laid out and hence to that
extent even in the past I think what we
have maintained is what I mean if the
market environment is favorable there is
no reason why we would not be able to
accelerate the expectation of combin and
that is where we are that is why we
stand and uh and and in all finel we
hope to kind of
achieve the thought process that we laid
out from a combin perspective it's it's
for the failure right that's the
clarification
I as and and prob we'll be in touch on
this P we believe the exit would be
overall the 50 B less there are serious
plans of Investments also we would uh
Continue to update as the quarters and
po because as gopal said these are early
signs that makes us optimistic and sees
the visibility of this but uh there are
multiple things that will unfold as of
now in our mind it will be probably exit
by quarter 4 is where we would see this
and if it gets further accelerated we
come back and uh connect with you all by
end of quarter one of this year great
thanks and all the
best thank
you we have the next question from the
line of maduk from noama w please go
ahead um hi congratulations on a good
set of numbers so most of my questions
have been answered I wanted to
understand uh investment yields have
improved uh again uh this quarter and
even if we
exclude um even if we exclude the
capital gains uh we're doing quite well
so uh what is the number that we should
be sort of looking at in this and uh
what is the duration how how are we
driving this actually that that is one
question on my own thank you sure M yeah
so again maduk I think uh again I would
kind of respond this in the context of
I'm sure you guys know this far better I
think obviously Investments have to be
looked at in terms of his return profile
over a period of time uh and hence to
that extent is how what we keep saying
is to look at Market opportunities in
terms of uh having a blended mix of the
right asset class es between both fixed
income and equity and that's what we
have been kind of looking at over the
period of time in terms of realizing the
opportunity now specifically to answer
your point on what led to let's say the
increase in the uh interest yield or
let's say the overall return on the
portfolio is is it is in line with the
high higher interest rate regime that we
have seen and obviously one leverages
the opportunity and even if you look at
historical part in terms of what kind of
a mix of our overall returns have been
in terms of interest acral to let's say
capital gains that mix has broadly been
on the inal side in the range of 75 to
80% and on the capital gain side a
number that could range between 15 to 20
20 20 25% around that kind of a
threshold so hence to that extent is how
we see the opportunity play out and
specifically if you look at our yield to
maturity uh on the fix income side the
yield to maturity currently stands at
about
7.4% uh so hence and that's the that's
the opportunity that one was able to
seize in the market and uh now can we
sustain this obviously we will have to
wait and see how the interest rate cycle
play out uh there are clear expectations
that you will start seeing some kind of
a rate reduction cycle play through at
some point of time again we are
positioned well even to capitalize that
opportunity but what could happen at
those points is our ability to reinvest
those uh realized flows we'll obviously
get invested at a lower return on the uh
approval side but obviously we are well
positioned to capitalize the opportunity
from a capital gains standpoint and
therefore now to your point on the
overall range of returns that we can
operate with again if you look at fi23 I
think the overall return on the realized
book was roughly at about 7.5% this
number if you look at for fi 24 was
roughly at about 7.98 closer to 8% um
and the range I mean internally the
range that we kind of run with is to
kind of give a return profile between 7
to 7 and a half% and but over our last
now that we are almost to 23rd 24th year
of operations I think the return profile
has been definitely better than that
particular range so that's the range
that we would be comfortable with and
hence that extent is where we would like
to operate
at thanks thanks very helpful thank you
thanks for
the thank
you ladies and gentlemen we will now
take the last question for today from
the line of additi josi from JP Morgan
please go
ahead uh yes sir thank you for my
question taking my question uh just one
follow question um which I wanted to uh
understand from you on the comp uh the
investment intensity in the channel uh
so for the uh F 2025 what is the Outlook
as been of the investment in the channel
uh in terms of the intensity are you
going to increase further or I just wait
for the Investments the last in the last
couple of years to cify and then just
some guidance on that will be helpful so
so see again if you look at I think what
we put out even as a part of the
introductory comment is I think just to
kind of refresh again I think we always
looked ourselves as a multi-distribution
uh company and therefore to that extent
is how we see opportunity play out
across different channels if you ask us
would we stay entrenched with each of
these channels the answer is clear yes I
think in so far as let's say as we see
new motor vehicle sales gaining momentum
and therefore to that extent obviously
we will kind of Leverage on the access
SL partnership that we have been able to
create historically of working with OEM
SL more importantly the dealership touch
points and that's the reason if you look
at across years the proportion of
dealership access that we have had out
of the total number of dealerships as a
country again just to kind of refresh
that number used to be between 50 to 55%
at the time when we did our listing
currently we have been able to reach
that number closer to slightly upward to
65% uh in terms of the total number of
leadership so that will continue to be
an important channel of distribution
agency which kind of encompasses between
motor
Health has always been an area of
opportunity and that's a segment which
obviously we have been kind of expanding
a lot more and clearly we have seen
benefits of the investment play out
whether you look at onme I think the
growth rates over the last several years
have been very positive even on let's
say I would say uh agency motor I think
that's a segment where we have talked
about trying to create a balanced mix
between dealership agency and let's say
our direct distribution so hence to that
extent obviously we will continue to
leverage on uh motage agency
specifically and in specific since we're
talking in the cont of agency retail
health is always positive opportunity
that one sees uh and that's the reason
why we put out that number of the head
count that we have on our own health
agency managers which is currently at
about, 1600 and we would want to
continue to see expansion in that
particular space so you will obviously
see a lot more expansion initiatives
being undertaken in the context of
retail health and therefore the that
should logically translate into an
improved market share uh in that
particular segment while even this year
we would have loved to have done better
but honestly we have not been able to
completely leverage the uh opportunity
that one sees but given the fact that we
have been able to uh strengthen our
leadership team as well I think one
would expect a lot more to happen in
terms of expanding distribution
launching new products and obviously
strengthening the technology
deliverables uh so that's so agency will
continue to be a very very important
channel of sourcing and sanjie in the
last earning calls did speak about one
is one digital uh Channel and therefore
that will again continue to be a very
very important channel of sourcing and
if you look at just from the current
year standpoint the overall contribution
of the digital opportunity that spans
across I take care website Alliance
Partners etc etc that contribution has
been almost in the range of about 6 to
7% of the overall revenues and that's
again kind of compounding well in in
exess of almost about 20% year on year
so all in all I think uh it is going to
be a combination of all channels I think
there is going to be thrust of
investments in each of them if you ask
me which channel we by far gain the
Maximum Traction obviously retail health
is an area where we would want to kind
of significantly leverage faster and
then of course we have the digital
opportunity that one sees and then we
will continue to leverage on the other
channels of and more importantly I just
I did miss one of them which is the bank
partnership I think again that will be a
very very important area of sourcing and
within that icsi group will be a very
very important contribution for us and
hence we would obviously want to
leverage on each of these channels of
distribution thank you very much can I
can I just squeeze in one more can you
pleas uh share your outlook of the
health pricing both in the retail and
the group that would be helpful thank
you outlook on
health uh pricing pricing the health
insurance presses yeah in both the
retail segment that's Rel in the group I
think uh it's it's it's a function of
loss ratio and as you said we will
continue to be a prudent underwriter in
both the segments most of the industry
including us have taken a hike on the
retail Health side last year so we would
believe as things stand we would like to
operate in this range uh and while we
will obviously keep revisiting in terms
of frequency as well as the losses show
that comes along with it but uh that's
what our view on retail health is the
group health is far more Dam than and uh
driven by multiple you know factors in
the market uh is it holding up overall
years there has been some bit of a
discipline that continues to exist and
if that's what stays then we would
obviously stay relevant if it does not
work out for us we would not hesitate to
move away and let go that business if
it's not making sense that Clarity we
have and you always I again reiterate
that uh profit pools keep moving uh and
accordingly we have to be agile as an
organization we will take those calls uh
uh because we want to to the best of our
effort want to ensure that we deliver
what the market is expecting with us
with a multi-line multiproduct company
like
us thank you very much thanks thank you
thank you I would now like to hand the
conference over to Mr sanjie mantri for
closing comments over to you sir now
thank you so much for joining in uh it's
an auspicious day of ram Navi and
probably some of your holidays uh it's
always a pleasure interacting with all
of you the opportunity as it stays the
momentum that we have developed we are
excited about the opportunity ahead uh
look forward to interacting with you in
time to come and all the best Take Care
thank you so
much thank you on behalf of ICI Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited
concludes this conference thank you all
for joining us you may now disconnect
your lines